Guide to the Leonard Solomon Silk papers, 1929-1995 and undated, bulk 1950-1985 RL.01187
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Accession 6096, 1933-1985, and undated, 86 boxes
  - Manuscripts (Box 143)
    - Unidentified manuscripts, 3 pieces, 30 pages total, mixed originals and xerox, heavily annotated (Box 143)
    - Silk, Leonard S. [probably], unidentified manuscript, originals and xerox copies, 366 pages (Box 143)
    - Synder, J. M., The Opec Crisis, Implications for the Investor, a speech presented before the National Committee for Monetary Reform Conference, Montreal, Canada, June 6, 1980, 10 page copy (Box 143)
    - Tapinos, G., Translated by Edward L. Morese, The World in the 1980s Project, prepared as a draft papter, January 26, 1976, 98 page xerox copy (Box 143)
    - Timmer, C. P., China and the World Food System, March, 1981, draft xerox xopy, 31 pages (Box 143)
  - Manuscripts (Box 144)
    - Vanderslice, T. A., Opening Remarks by Thomas A. Vanderslice, Chairman, Sub-Committee on Technology Policy in the United States, Committee for Economic Development and the President and Chief Operating Officer of General Telephone and Electronics Corporation, Congressional Seminar, June 18, 1980 on the Role of R and D in the Performance of U.S. Economy, 5 page xerox copy (Box 144)
    - Verzariu, P., Lenz, A. J., Theriot, L., Lamb, D., Martins, J., The Role of Equity Capital in East-West Economic Cooperation, paper prepared for: Senior Economic Advisers to ECE Governments, Seminar on Forms and Orientations of International Cooperation in Relation to Long-term Growth Patterns, program #D-27, a staff paper, January, 1979, xerox copy, 15 pages (Box 144)
    - Vogel, E. F., The Challenge from Japan, for the conference on U.S. Competitiveness, April 25, 1980, copy, 9 pages (Box 144)
    - Walker, C. E., Letter To the Editor, August 1, 1980, xerox copy, 2 pages (Box 144)
    - Wallich, H. C., and Dod, D. P., Foreign Assistance Programs and Policies of the United States, International Finance Discussion Papers, number 166, August, 1980, K.7, 28 pages, copy (Box 144)
    - Wriston, W. B., Annual Meeting Remarks, Chairman, Citicorp, Chicago, IL, April 18, 1978, copy of typewritten manuscript, 14 pages (Box 144)
    - n.a., The Classical Economic Case for Cutting Marginal Income Tax Rates, undated, xerox copy of typewritten manuscript with inserted newspaper clipping, 65 pages (Box 144)
    - n.a., Energy Problems of Japan, issued by the Embassy of Japan, Washington, DC, April 28, 1980, copy, inscribed, 7 pages (Box 144)
    - n.a., Patent and Trademark Protection in China, March 16, 1979, 6 page copy (Box 144)
    - n.a., Recession-Recovery Watch, the 13th in an ongoing series of reports designed to assist in the evaluation of current business condition, issued by the Center for International Business Cycle Research, Rutgers University, Newark, NJ, June 8, 1981, 12 page copy (Box 144)
  - Monograph (Box 144)
    - Barnett, A. D., China and the World Food System, published and copyrighted by the Overseas Development Council, Washington, DC, April 1979, Monograph #12, 65 pages (Box 144)
  - News Releases, 1978, April 18 - 1981, May 18, and undated, 8 items (Box 144)
  - Notebooks (Box 144)
    - Stillman, S., The Economic and Political Philosophy of the Business Corporation, August 3, 1973 (Box 144)
    - International Corporate Leadership Seminar, 1980, issued by the Aspen Institute for Humanistic Studies, with index tabs (Box 144)
    - Untitled, correspondence to: John Applegrath, from: Willis W. Harman, date: July 28, 1982 (Box 144)
  - Notes (Box 145)
    Handwritten and typed, 40 pages.
  - Offering Circulars and Prospectuses (Box 145)
    - The New York Times Company Employee Stock Purchase Plan, 1981 offering, booklet (Box 145)
  - Packets (Box 145)
    - The American Economic System, Information and Action Guide, a Public Service Campaign by the Advertising Council, Inc., 51 items including packet, booklets, brochures, news releases, fliers, radio program listings, bulletins, reports, advertisements, fact sheets, undated (Box 145)
    - Boston University School of Management, 6 items including news release, report booklet, order form, and the following correspondence: to: Leonard S. Silk from: Michael R. Jones, April 21, 1981 (Box 145)
    - The Club of Rome Conference, April 12-14, 1976, co-sponsored by the First Pennsylvania Corporation, The Franklin Institute, The Philadelphia Chapter of the Institute of Electrical and Electronic Engineers, held at the University of Pennsylvania Museum, Harrison Auditorium, 19 items including booklet, brochure, bulletin, clipping, and background paper (Box 145)
  - Periodicals (Box 145)
    - The AFL-CIA American Federationist, May 1980, vol. 87, no. 5, published monthly by the American Federation of Labor and Congress of Industrial Organizations, Washington, DC (Box 145)
    - Across the Board, the Conference Board Magazine, published monthly by the Conference Board, Inc., NY, NY: May, 1978, vol. 15, no. 5; May 1981, vol. 18, no. 5 (Box 145)
    - The American Economic Review, published by the American Economic Association, Menasha, WI: February, 1977, vol. 67, no. 1; September, 1979, vol. 69, no. 4 (Box 145)
    - Business Week, McGraw-Hill, Inc., NY, NY: July 6, 1981, no. 2695; August 17, 1981, no. 2701 (Box 145)
    - CEI Newsletter, published by the Claremont Economics Institute, Claremont, CA, August 12, 1981 (Box 145)
    - Challenge, the Magazine of Economic Affairs, vol. 17, no. 2, May/June, 1974, published by International Arts and Sciences Press, Inc., White Plains, NY (Box 145)
    - Chemical and Engineering News, July 20, 1981, vol. 59, no. 29, published by the American Chemical Society, Washington, DC (Box 145)
    - The China Business Review, March-April, 1979, vol. 6, no. 2, published by the National Council for US-China Trade, Washington, DC, 2 copies (Box 145)
    - The Civil Liberties Review, March/April, 1978, vol. 4, no. 6, published by the American Civil Liberties Union Foundation, NY, NY (Box 145)
    - Columbia Journalism Review, July/August `980, vol. 19, no. 2, published bt the Graduate School of Journalism, Columbia University, Marion, OH (Box 145)
    - Commentary, published by the American Jewish Committee, NY, NY: February, 1978, vol. 65, no. 2; April, 1978, vol. 65, no. 4; June, 1981, vol. 71, no. 6 (Box 145)
    - Computers of the Times, vol. 4, no. 1, August 3, 1981, n.p (Box 145)
  - Periodicals (Box 148)
    - The New York Times Magazine, published by the New York Times, NY, NY: March 26, 1978, section 6; July 27, 1980, section 6; August 3, 1980, section 6 (Box 148)
    - The New York Times School Weekly, Background Supplement, published by the New York Times Company, NY, NY, November 28, 1977, Section II (Box 148)
    - Newswatch, published by the American Council for Capital Formation, Washington, DC: June 1980, vol. 5, no. 6; July 1980, vol. 5, no. 7 (Box 148)
    - The OECD Observer, published by OECD Ministerial Council, June 3-4, 1980 (Box 148)
    - Princeton Alumni Weekly, published by Princeton University Press, Princeton, NJ: June 2, 1980, vol. 80, no. 19 (Box 148)
    - The Public Interest, published by National Affairs, Inc., NY, NY, Special Edition, 1980 (Box 148)
    - The Saturday Review/World, published by Saturday Review/World, Inc., NY, NY, January 26, 1974, vol. 1, no. 10 (Box 148)
    - Saturday Review, published by Saturday Review Magazine Corp., NY, NY, July 9, 1977, vol. 4 no. 20 (Box 148)
  - Periodicals - Clippings, 1973-1981, and undated (Box 148)
  - Publications - Excerpts, 3 items (Box 148)
  - Photographs (Box 148)
    - 8" x 10" black and white photograph of a Junior High School sports team; Leonard S. Silk is pictured on the front row, 4th person on the right, description and identification attached, xerox copy (Box 148)
  - Programs (Box 148)
    - Commencement Recital, Duke University Chapel, Fenner Douglas, University Organist and Professor of Music, the Benjamin N. Duke Memorial Organ, Flentrop, 1976, Saturday, May 6, 1978, 126th Commencement (Box 148)
    - Committee on Science and Technology, U.S. House of Representatives, Washington, DC, Seminar on Research, Productivity and the National Economy, June 18. 1980, Washington, DC (Box 148)
    - Leveson, I., Corporate Environment Program: Issues for the 1980s, A Decade of Decision: The U.S. Economic Outlook for the 1980s and Beyond, May, 1980 (Box 148)
    - Council on Foreign Relations, Inc. Meeting in honor of Leonard Silk, December 22, 1976 (Box 148)
  - Reports (Box 148)
    - Conference on U.S. Competitiveness, April 15, 1980, Seminar #1 Abstract: International Trade, 2 copies (Box 148)
  - Reprints (Box 148)
    - Brams, S. J., Fishburn, P. C., Approval Voting, from The American Political Science Review, vol. 72, no. 3, September, 1978, pages 831-847 (Box 148)
    - Spengler, J. J., Economist vs. Legist, Politician, Bureaucrat, Atlantic Economic Journal, vol. 2, no. 2, November 1974 (Box 148)
    - Declining Population Growth: Economic Effects; Robinson, W. C., Comment, Commission on Population Growth and The American Future Research Reports, vol. 2, Economic Aspects of Population Change (Box 148)
    - Evolution, Welfare, and Time in Economics, Essays in Honor of Nicholas Georgescu-Roegen, edited by Anthony M. Tang, Fred M. Westfield, and James S. Worley of Vanderbilt University, published by Lexington Books, D.C. Heath and Company, Lexington, MA (Box 148)
    - General Series Reprint, published by the Brookings Institution, Washington, DC, issues and numbers listed as follows:
      - #282, Brown, S. and Fabian, L. L., Diplomats at Sea, 1974 (Box 148)
      - #283, Hartman, R. W., The Rationale for Federal Support for Higher Education, 1974 (Box 148)
      - #284, Pechman, J. A., International Trends in the Distribution of Tax Burdens: Implications for Tax Policy, 1974 (Box 148)
      - #285, Hartman, R. W., Financing the Opportunity to Enter the 'Educated Labor Market', 1974 (Box 148)
      - #287, McKie, J. W., The Ends and Means of Regulation, 1974 (Box 148)
      - #288, Rivlin, A. M., Social Policy: Alternate Strategies for the Federal Government, 1974 (Box 148)
      - #313, Reischaur, R. D., General Revenue Sharing: The Program's Incentives, 1976 (Box 148)
      - #315, Sanderson, F. H., Export Opportunities for Agricultural Products: Implications for U.S. Agriculture and Trade Policies, 1976 (Box 148)
      - #317, Davis, K., Equal Treatment and Unequal Benefits, The Medicare Program, 1976 (Box 148)
      - #319, Gramlich, E. M., The New York City Fiscal Crisis: What Happened and What is to be Done? 1977 (Box 148)
      - #320, Conflicting National Goals, by Arthur M. Okun, 1977 (Box 148)
      - #321, Musgrove, P., Latin American Energy Supply and the United States, 1977 (Box 148)
      - #322, Russell, R. B., The Diffusion of New Hospital Technologies in the United States, 1977 (Box 148)
      - #324, Denison, E. F., The Contribution of Capital to the Postwar Growth of Industrial Countries, 1977 (Box 148)
    - Spengler, J., Was 1922-1972 a Golden Age in the History of Economics? Journal of Economic Issues, Vol. 8, no. 3, September, 1974 (Box 148)
    - Bernays, E. L., Uncle Sigi, Journal of the History of Medicine and Allied Sciences, vol. 35, no. 2, April, 1980 (Box 148)
    - Spengler, J., Malthusianism Old and New: The Prospect, Institute on Nutrition, The University of North Carolina, March, 1978, vol. 1, no. 12, 2 copies (Box 148)
    - Cost of Specialization in a Service Economy, Social Science Quarterly, September, 1970 (Box 148)
    - Economics: Its Direct and Indirect Impacts in America, 1776-1976, Social Science Quarterly, June 1976, vol. 57, no. 1, pages 49-76 (Box 148)
    - Evolution of Public Utility Industry Regulation: Economists and Other Determinants, The South African Journal of Economics, vol. 37, no. 1, March, 1969, pages 3-31 (Box 148)
    - The State of the City, The New York Times, May 11-25, 1975 (Box 148)
    - Spengler, J., Stationary Population: Economic and Education Implications, Canadian Studies in Population, vol. 2, 1975, pages 1-14 (Box 148)
  - Transcripts (Box 148)
    - Paul Volcker interview, WNET/Thirteen, NY, NY, transcripts of the MacNeil-Lehrer Report, Library #1539, Show #7039, xerox copy, August 20, 1981 (Box 148)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 148)
    - Business cards for Seymour C. Hyman and C. Peter Timmer (Box 148)
    - Editorial research reports, Daily Service, Washington, DC, June 14, 1973 (Box 148)
    - Leibenstein, H., Selective Rationality and Neoclassical Theory Contrasted, Harvard University, undated (Box 148)
  - Book Review Requests (Box 148)
    - The Brookings Institution, Washington, DC, August 8, 1977 (Box 148)
    - Pomper, G. M. with colleagues, The Election of 1980, Reports and Interpretations, Chatham House Publishers, Inc., Chatham, NJ, May 1981 (Box 148)
    - Kane, R. S., Africa A to Z Revised, Doubleday and Company, Inc., NY, NY, October, 20, 1972 (Box 148)
    - The Pharmaceutical Industry: Economics, Performance, and Government Regulation, Hoffmann-La Roche Inc., Nutley, NJ, March 1, 1978, published by John Wiley and Sons (Box 148)
    - Petit, Freedom in the American Economy, Richard D. Irwin, Inc., Homewood, IL, for review in Business Week, 1964 (Box 148)
    - Consumer's Union Report on Smoking and the Public Interest, the Consumer's Union, Simon and Schuster Publishers, NY, NY, July 17, 1963 (Box 148)
    - Pantheon Books, unidentified book (Box 148)
    - Praeger Publishers, NY, NY, November 30, 1971, unidentified book (Box 148)
    - Schultz, T. W., Economic Crises in World Agriculture, The University of Michigan Press, Ann Arbor, MI, April 2, 1965 (Box 148)
- Accession 2008-0039, 1946-1995, bulk 1976-1995; 1 folder
  Addition (08-039) (32 items, .1 lin. ft.; dated 1946-1995, bulk 1976-1995) comprises primarily correspondence, but includes some comments and addresses made by Silk and others. Topics include his nomination to the Century Club (1976), comments made at a reception held in his honor by the City University of New York (1994), and condolences sent to his wife, Bernice, following Silk's death in 1995.
  - File of correspondence, writings (addresses, comments), and condolences (Folder Sec. A Box 120)